Hi, in this lesson, you will learn about Edge and First mode in Google Antigravity.
This is fun of the agent modes that help you complete simple task really quickly without
sacrificing too much quality.
So let's talk first, what is the Edge and Mode?
Yeah.
If you open the commentation, you don't find the much information about it.
So I gonna give you some, my practical example, so my understanding what is it.
Edge and Mode is designed for speed.
Now when you activate this mode, the Edge and Executes all tasks directly without spending
extra time on planning overification, so it's perfect when you need something done right
now.
And the task is straightforward enough that you don't need extra safety checks.
So when you should use Ask mode, sorry, First mode, First mode works best for simple localized
tasks that you can easily verify yourself.
For example, renaming variables through a code, running a few batch commands or making
small code adjustments.
This task where speed matters, more than having AI double check every detail, yep.
You want to change this mat quickly so we can keep moving forward with your work.
Oh, let me show you some use cases on practice.
So some tasks which work great with Fast mode, we have examples with common dark class and
I will show you what type of tasks I can do with Fast mode and what is the best.
So the first one is renaming methods or variables, yep, it's really a simple task.
Imagine we want to make a method names more descriptive, let's say we'd like to rename
get months, method to get current months to be more explicit, yep, and this is a perfect
fast mode task.
It's of course really simple so we can do it by ourselves, yep.
But imagine you have a bigger code base where you need to do a 10, 20, 50 replacement
so the fast mode is good for you.
I will choose the fast mode right here and I will paste my prompt, yep.
Let's say our names get months, method to get current months, and let's see how it will
work.
So it's thought, or we can always check what is his thoughts and he's currently analyzing
the current double JS method and his update in the code.
For example, you can also use it when you'd like to create a better name for your method,
yep.
If you don't know how to name your method, you can also use the fast mode.
As you see it did replacement, it replaces the name of the method and also the usage of
this method.
Oh, it's fine, yep.
And you can see the details, yep.
He also shows the example of code where he did renaming.
You can also see right here that one file was changed.
If you click on it, you can make review changes.
And then in review changes mod, yep, you will see the red lines which was, this is the
code was removed and the green line, the code was added or replaced.
Yeah, and you can see visually what the changes are.
If you have changes in more files, you of course can scroll down and be changes across
all the files.
And here you see how much lines was added and was removed.
You can also expand and collapse it if you have to review a lot of files.
Well, next, so we can close it right here are you have a few options how you can accept
it.
So we can do it line by line.
For example, you can click accept here or you can then click accept here or when you hover
on it.
Yeah, this is how we can do it or you can accept everything at once right here.
You just can switch between the file changes.
Yeah, and if you back you will see changes or you and you can click accept or reject
all.
I will click accept all, so the other use case is let me think what can be another use case.
It's adding the simple helper methods.
So sometimes you need it quickly, you delete the method that doesn't require some complex
logic.
For instance, you might want the methods that the tools formatted date string.
Yeah, so we can type it to to agent, let me just copy paste the prompt.
So I'm here working in the same chat because the task are really simple and they relate
to one class so that's why I don't need to switch between chats.
But if you work on bigger features, it's of course better to switch between chats when
you have a lot of context.
So I'm going to ask about another task.
So let's wait a bit.
Yeah, you see he created a get from a data date and he used, he reused some of the methods
as it's nice.
And if we see the review, yeah, when we click here, we also switch to this file.
And we see here use the get from a data date and under the hood, it used already this
class methods to get the formatted data.
So I can click accept because it's on the one line and right here, I can also click.
Okay, like those have it.
No, why it's yes, it was I think a small bug in anti-gravity, so we just close the file
and open it again and everything now is fine, so get from a data date, no, it's not used.
So if you have this issue like you try to save it, you wasn't able, something gone wrong,
so you can ask the follow up questions in your chat.
It's also very useful is use this method, so we can ask very simple question because
we already asked before what method, you know what method he added, so he's in context.
In that case this short questions will work, yeah, and you see he did the replacement.
I can click accept all, and you see all code is accepted.
So what else, for example, you could like to add some login in your file, you'd like to
add some console logs right here, yeah, like console log just for some debugging, yeah, you
can also ask to add it in the first mode, you'd like to update some of the tool values,
for example, instead of one string you want to return another string, so you can do some
small and simple tasks, yeah, okay, now we know how to accept and reject changes, how
to ask follow up questions, so after you accept all the changes, what is really good is test
your code to make sure everything works correctly, you can run your application to verify
that the calendar still renders properly with the rename it methods, we can notice an issue
after a set and you can always ask the agent to fix it, or like use and do in your editor
to reverse the changes, okay, you can always if you'd like to undo, you can for example
hover in your chat and you can click and do changes like in the message you sent, so you
can revert to the previous state and if I click, I can confirm and you see it back, so now
I don't see the method is used, yeah, okay, that's good, I will use it by myself, so let's
wrap up, you can use fast mode when the task is really simple, if you can describe what
you need in one sentence, for instance, the main benefit of fast mode is speed, task complete
faster because the agent skips the extra planning and reviews that, however this comes
with a trade-off, the quality might not be high as other mode, especially for complex
tasks, like for an aiming you see it works perfectly, yeah, but if you try to run it for
asking like to write a big class with a lot of methods, it might be delivers the wrong
result, for example, yeah, in that case better to use planning mode to issue you, overview
in the next lesson, yeah, and so, and see you in the next lesson then.